# SHARADA JAYAWEERA

# DEVOPS ENGINEER

+358 417235222

sharada.prabash@gmail.com

Orivedenkatu 8F 113, 33720 Tampere

www.linkedin.com/in/ in sharada-jayaweera



https:// sharadajay.github.io/

DevOps Engineer, with experience Software in Development with Java, Spring Boot, Angular, Python, Go (Golang), Cloud Services, CI/CD toolchain and Identity and Access Management (IAM). Known for excellent problem solving skills and creative solutions to solve complex challenges. A forward-thinking professional, always pushing the boundaries of technology to deliver impactful results.

# **EXPERIENCES**

### SENIOR DEVOPS ENGINEER

Aug. 2023 - Nov. 2023

## Axiata Digital Labs (Pvt) Ltd. I Sri Lanka

- Managed and maintained a customized IAM solution built on top of WSO2 Identity Server with Single Sign-On (SSO) functionality.
- Worked as a full-stack developer for ADL Axonect Enabler platform Enterprise team (https://axonect.com/axonect-enterprise-enabler/).

#### **DEVOPS ENGINEER**

Axiata Digital Labs (Pvt) Ltd. I Sri Lanka

Jun. 2021 - Aug. 2023

- Worked as a full-stack developer for ADL Axonect Enterprise Enabler platform team.
- Worked as a L3 Support Engineer managing GCP Cloud Infrastructure, CI/CD tools, Software Deployments and Application Monitoring (Dynatrace, Cloud dashboards).
- Worked as an Research Engineer to develop a Network Management and Orchestration Tool for modern networks (4G/5G) leveraging ONAP, OSM and FREE5GC.
- Designed and developed a fully event-driven system using AWS Lambda functions, S3, EventBridge, CloudWatch, SNS, KMS and IAM. Created CloudFormation templates

#### **R&D ENGINEERING INTERN**

Jun. 2019 - Dec. 2019

Centre for Smart Systems (CS2), Singapore University of Technology and Design (SUTD) I Singapore

• Developed devices for Air Quality monitoring, designed enclosures using SOLIDWORKS and developed Mobile Applications using Android Studio and Flutter for the configuration and data visualization of the devices.



# EDUCATION

# University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

2016 - 2021 | BSc Eng Hons in Electronic and Telecommunication Engineering

# SKILLS

# **Programming & Scripting Languages**

- Java
- Go (Golang)
- Python
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Bash

# Frameworks & Libraries

- Spring Boot
- Angular React
- Gin
- Django

# **Cloud Services**

- AWS
- GCP
- OpenStack
- Azure

# **Container Technologies**

- Docker
- Kubernetes
- Helm

## **CI/CD & Version Control Tools**

- Git
- Jenkins
- GitLab
- GitHub

### **DevOps**

- Terraform
- Linux
- Ansible
- Nginx

### **Databases**

- MySQL
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL
- Redis

### **APIs**

REST

GraphQL

# **Identity & Access Management (IAM)**

- OAuth 2.0
- OpenID Connect
- Single Sign-On (SSO)
- (OIDC)

# LANGUAGES

English Proficient (C1)

Finnish Basic (A1.3)